<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<hipertext xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
		   xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="HH.xsd">
	<definition>
		Hipertext is a nonlinear text material.
	</definition>
	<history>
		<person>
			<name>Vannevar</name>
			<surname>Bush</surname>
			<birth>1890</birth>
			<death>1974</death>
			<image source="img/Vannevar-Bush.jpg">Vannevar Bush</image>
			<about>
				Vannevar Bush was a famous scientist in his days and was the science advisor to President Roosevelt during the Second World War, when science-based issues like inventing nuclear weapons were of great importance. After "As We May Think" ran in the Atlantic Monthly , it caused considerable discussion, and both Time and Life ran stories on the  Memex. Life even had an artist draw up illustrations of how the Memex would look and a scenario of its projection positions as the user was completing a link. Doug Engelbart,  who later became a pioneer in the development of interactive computing and invented the mouse, got part of his inspiration by reading Bush's article while waiting for a ship home from the Philippines in 1945. In spite of all this early interest surrounding the Memex it never got built. As hinted above, our current computer technology is still not able to support Bush's vision in its entirety. We do have computers with most of the Memex functionality but they are based on a completely different technology from the microfilm discussed by Bush.
			</about>
			<achievements>
				<achievement n="1">
					<title>Memex - "memory extender"</title>
					<description>
						Bush described the Memex as "a sort of mechanized private file and library" and as "a device in which an individual stores his books, records, and communications, and which is mechanized so that it may be consulted with exceeding speed and flexibility." The Memex would store this information on microfilm, which would be kept in the user's desk. This desk was intended to have several microfilm projection positions to enable the user to compare different microfilms, in a manner very similar to the windows that became popular on personal computers more than forty years later. The Memex would have a scanner to enable the user to input new material, and it would also allow the user to make handwritten marginal notes and comments. But Bush envisaged that most of the Memex contents are purchased on microfilm ready for insertion. Books of all sorts, pictures, current periodicals, newspapers, are thus obtained and dropped into place. Business correspondence takes the same path. Actually we have not yet reached the state of hypertext development where there is a significant amount of preprocessed information for sale that can be integrated with a user's existing hypertext structure.
					</description>
				</achievement>
			</achievements>
		</person>
		<person>
			<name>Tim</name>
			<surname>Berners-Lee</surname>
			<birth>1955</birth>
			<image source="img/Tim.jpg">Sir Tim Berners-Lee</image>
			<achievements>
				<achievement n="1">
					<title>HTML</title>
					<description>
						Hypertext Markup Language - The markup (formatting) language for the web.
					</description>
				</achievement>
				<achievement n="2">
					<title>URI</title>
					<description>
						Uniform Resource Identifier. A kind of "address" that is unique and used to identify to each resource on the web.
					</description>
				</achievement>
				<achievement n="3">
					<title>HTTP</title>
					<description>
						Hypertext Transfer Protocol. Allows for the retrieval of linked resources from across the web.
					</description>
				</achievement>
				<achievement n="4">
					<title>browser</title>
				</achievement>
			</achievements>
		</person>
	</history>
	<course>
		<student>
			<name>student's name</name>
			<surname>student's surname </surname>
		</student>
		<classes kind="lecture" >
			<component id="2">
				<topic>Hypertext and hypermedia</topic>
				<theme>Hypertext &amp; hypermedia</theme>
				<theme>HTML CSS</theme>
				<theme>XML</theme>
				<theme>XML Schema</theme>
				<theme>DTD</theme>
				<theme>XSLT</theme>
				<score>30</score>
			</component>
		</classes>
		<classes kind="laboratory" obligatory="yes">
			<component id="1">
				<topic>HTML + CSS</topic>
				<theme>structure of the page</theme>
				<theme>links</theme>
				<theme>forms</theme>
				<theme>css</theme>
				<score>10</score>
			</component>
			<component id="2">
				<topic>XML + XML Schema</topic>
				<theme>correctly formed XML file</theme>
				<theme>creating a hierarchy</theme>
				<theme>declaring elements, attributes</theme>
				<theme>defining types</theme>
				<theme>validating XML file</theme>
				<score>10</score>
			</component>
			<component id="3">
				<topic>XSLT</topic>
				<theme>XML -> HTML transformation</theme>
				<theme>XML -> XML transformation</theme>
				<score>10</score>
			</component>
		</classes>
		<classes kind="project">
			<component id="1">
				<topic>HTML, XML, XML Schema, DTD</topic>
				<score>25</score>
			</component>
			<component id="2">
				<topic>XML, XSLT</topic>
				<score>15</score>
			</component>
		</classes>
		<information>
			<links>
				<link source="https://www.w3schools.com/html/">HTML w3schools</link>
				<link source="https://www.w3schools.com/xml/default.asp">XML w3schools</link>
				<link source="https://enauczanie.pg.edu.pl/moodle/">Moodle</link>
			</links>
		</information>
	</course>
</hipertext>